volunteermatch.org 2012-10-04

# VolunteerMatch - VolunteerMatch Privacy Policy

**Our Commitment To Privacy**  
Your privacy is important to us. Our ongoing commitment to the protection of your privacy is essential to maintaining the relationship of trust that exists between VolunteerMatch, Inc. and all of our users, whether they be a nonprofit or other volunteer organization seeking volunteers (each, an "Agency"), volunteers, volunteers with a personalized account, readers of our newsletters or other visitors to this Web site. This privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy") is intended to help you understand our online information security practices. 

**The Information We Collect**  
You may have accessed VolunteerMatch directly by visiting our Web site, the home page of which is located at www.volunteermatch.org, or through the Web site of one of our third-party partners with whom we have teamed to provide volunteering services, such as (a) your employer; (b) a VolunteerMatch co-branding partner; or (c) a corporate partner (collectively, "Partners"). This notice applies to all information you submit to VolunteerMatch through the VolunteerMatch Web site. Please note that we cannot be responsible for the information you submit directly to third parties, including our Partners, who may have their own posted policies regarding the collection and use of your information. We urge you to review the policies of our Partners through whom you may access our services. 

The types of information including without limitation, personal information ("Information") we may collect are: 

  * For Newsletter Subscribers: 
    * First and Last Name
    * Email address
  * For volunteers without a personal VolunteerMatch account who have accessed VolunteerMatch through www.volunteermatch.org or a Partner's Web site: 
    * First and Last Name
    * Email address
    * Telephone number
    * Address, City and State (optional)
    * Zip Code
    * Comments about volunteer opportunity (optional)
    * Other categories of information required or requested by an Agency to register for a particular volunteer opportunity.
  * For volunteers with a personal VolunteerMatch account who have accessed VolunteerMatch through www.volunteermatch.org or a Partner's Web site: 
    * First and Last Name
    * Email address
    * Telephone number
    * Address, City and State (optional)
    * Zip Code
    * Comments about volunteer opportunity (optional)
    * Username and Password
    * Referral history
    * Customized email preferences (optional)
    * Resume (optional)
    * Feedback and comments
    * Other categories of information required or requested by an Agency to register for a particular volunteer opportunity.
  * For volunteers with a personal VolunteerMatch account who have accessed VolunteerMatch through a Partner's Web site where "Hours Tracking" (a tool for individuals to record their volunteer hours) and/or "Special Event Manager" (a registration and response tool for volunteering events) are enabled: 
    * First and Last Name
    * Email address
    * Telephone number
    * Home Address, City and State (optional)
    * Home Zip Code
    * Employee Information chosen by a corporate Partner, including without limitation Employee ID; Employee Position Information (Status, Title, Level, Business Unit, Division, Location, Department, Immediate Supervisor); Employee Office Information (Office, Mail Code/Mail Stop, Address, City, State, Zip Code, Telephone Number)
    * Information Regarding the Agency that Received Your Services - Agency Name; Address; City; State; Telephone Number; Fax; Web site Address; Description of Services; Mission Statement; Tax ID/EIN 
    * Additional Information Regarding Agencies - Contact Information (Contact Title, First and Last Name, Telephone Number, Email); 
    * Opportunity Information (Type, Description, Duration) (optional)
    * Volunteer Event Information - Accomplishments; Skills Used; Paid Time Off; Dollars for Doers; Team Grant Name; Team Grant Beneficiary; Number of Clients Served Under Median Income; Role in Activity (optional)
    * Comments about opportunity (optional)
    * Referral history
    * Customized email preferences (optional)
    * Resume (optional)
    * Feedback and comments
    * Other categories of information required or requested by an Agency to register for a particular volunteer opportunity.
  * For Nonprofit Organizations: 
    * Administrator Information - First and Last Name; Email; Telephone Number; Zip Code; Username and Password. Address; City; State (optional)
    * Agency Information - Agency Name; Contact Information (Contact Title, First and Last Name, Telephone Number, Address, City, State, Zip Code, Email); Description Of Services; Mission Statement; Tax ID/EIN; Affiliations; Volunteer Type Category. Web site Address; Fax (optional).
    * Volunteer Opportunity Information - Opportunity Title; Contact Email; Description; Volunteer Type; Location Information (either Street Location or "Virtual" Designation). Required Skills; Date; Time; Commitment Information; Volunteer Age; Group Size (optional).
    * Feedback and comments

**User Consent**  

By submitting Information through our Web site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the processing of your Information according to this Privacy Policy and you agree to the VolunteerMatch Terms of Service located at <http://www.volunteermatch.org/legal/terms.jsp> (the "Terms of Service").

Your Information may be processed by us in the country where it was collected as well as other countries (including the United States) where laws regarding processing of Information may be less stringent than the laws in your country.

**How We Use Information**  

We do not sell, rent or trade our volunteer, administrator, nonprofit, or general newsletter email addresses to outside parties. We use the Information we collect about you to facilitate the volunteering process and to provide information to you about VolunteerMatch and related industry topics. We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive.

Please be aware that, to the extent required to provide our services, we share your Information with volunteers, Agencies, or our Partners, as applicable. We also reserve the right to use your Information to send you e-mails regarding system downtime and/or changes to this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Service, and you are not permitted to opt out of receiving these e-mail messages. We will also use Information for the purpose you provide, for instance to sign you up for the Adopt-A-Zip-Code program.

Otherwise we use your Information in the following ways: 

  * For Newsletter Subscribers: 

We may use our email lists for sending out our newsletter and other VolunteerMatch outbound communications, such as product enhancements, tool upgrades, or membership news. 

  * For volunteers without a personal VolunteerMatch account who have accessed VolunteerMatch through www.volunteermatch.org or a Partner's Web site: 

If you indicate to us that you are interested in a particular volunteer opportunity and provide us with your Information, either through www.volunteermatch.org or a Partner's Web site, we will forward your Information to the Agency that is hosting that opportunity so that the Agency can contact you regarding your potential involvement, and, if the particular Agency (including an Agency that is a Partner) has a regional or national office or is closely affiliated with or a member of a related Agency (each, an "Affiliate"), then we may also share your Information with the applicable Affiliate. 

To the extent that you have provided any Information to us through our Web site regarding volunteer opportunities associated with one of our Partners, we may share your Information and referral history with the applicable Partner. Each of our Partners has its own policies regarding the collection and use of personal information, and VolunteerMatch is not responsible for their use of your Information. Furthermore, our Partners may collect additional information from you, independent of VolunteerMatch.org, in connection with the volunteer services. 

  * Additionally, for volunteers with a personal VolunteerMatch account who have accessed VolunteerMatch through www.volunteermatch.org or a Partner's Web site: 

If you indicate to us that you are interested in creating a personalized account, the information we gather from you will be used to permit you to: access the account, customize outbound email services, review your referral history and/or post a resume that can be sent as an attachment to inquiries you make using the VolunteerMatch service. 

For volunteers who have accessed VolunteerMatch through a Partner's Web site where Hours Tracking and/or Special Event Manager are enabled: If you indicate to us that you are interested in a particular volunteer opportunity and provide us with your Information via your employer's intranet, we will forward your Information to the Agency, or Affiliate, that is hosting that opportunity so that the Agency can contact you regarding your potential involvement. 

We share your Information with your employer so that your employer may log the number of hours you have volunteered during a specified period of time ("Hours"). In some instances, your employer may share your Information with third-party service providers to help your employer process data regarding your Hours. Your employer has its own policies regarding the use of your Information, and VolunteerMatch is not responsible for your employer's use of your Information. Furthermore, your employer may collect additional information from you, independent of VolunteerMatch.org, in connection with the volunteer services. 

  * For Agencies: 

If you submit Information to us as an Agency, then, subject to the terms and conditions as a nonprofit member of VolunteerMatch, your Information (excluding your EIN number) will be accessible by anyone who accesses VolunteerMatch. In addition, we may share your Information, including your EIN number, with selected Partners in order to verify your Agency's identity and tax status. 

Agencies who receive email addresses from potential volunteer signups are strongly encouraged to adopt privacy standards similar to those of VolunteerMatch. Each such Agency, however, has its own policies regarding collection and use of personal information and we are not responsible for their use of your Information. Inappropriate use of personal information received from VolunteerMatch may jeopardize nonprofit membership with VolunteerMatch. VolunteerMatch reserves the right to determine, in its discretion, what constitutes inappropriate use of this information. For more about an Agency's policy, please contact them directly using the contact information posted for that Agency on our Web site. 

  * In all cases, we use information provided by you for the purposes you provided the information. For instance, if you e-mail us with questions, we may use the information in your e-mail to answer the question. If you provide comments or feedback, we may publicly post those comments or feedback. 

If you submit Information to us as an Agency, then, subject to the terms and conditions as a nonprofit member of VolunteerMatch, your Information (excluding your EIN number) will be accessible by anyone who accesses VolunteerMatch. In addition, we may share your Information, including your EIN number, with selected Partners in order to verify your Agency's identity and tax status. 

Please note that any feedback or comments provided by you on the Web site may be generally accessibly by any visitor to the Web site. Therefore, please take care when posting feedback or comments to the site, as you will forfeit the privacy of that information. 

**Children's Privacy**  
We welcome Volunteers of all ages, including children under the age of thirteen. Due to our status as a non-profit organization, we are not required to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). However, we strongly encourage our volunteers aged thirteen and under to use our services only with parental consent and supervision. 

**Cookies**  
Cookies are tiny data files that Web sites commonly write to your hard drive when you visit them so that they can remember you when you visit. A cookie file contains information that can identify you anonymously and maintain your account's privacy. Our site uses cookies to maintain a user's identity between sessions so that the site can be personalized based on user preferences or a user's history. You can set your Web browser to prompt you before you accept a cookie, accept cookies automatically or reject all cookies.Â  However, if you choose not to accept cookies from this Web site, then you may not be able to access and use all or part of this Web site or benefit from the information and services which it offers. 

**Third-party Access and Use**  
Occasionally, we or our Partners hire third-party service providers to help provide or improve the services we offer you. Sometimes it is necessary for these providers to have access to the Information we collect about you. In those cases, we take reasonable steps to ensure that these providers do not use or otherwise disclose any Information we collect about you except for the purpose of fulfilling their service obligations to us and our Partners. We may share your Information with third-party service providers in connection with the following: 

  * Some of our Partners will match your volunteer hours contribution with a donation. In such cases, third-party service providers may be hired to help calculate the Partner's donation amount.
  * Our Partners may also hire third-party service providers to help coordinate volunteer events. We may share information with these third-party service providers in order to facilitate coordination of these events.
  * Information collected from Agencies may be shared with other websites, in order to promote volunteer events.

We share aggregate information about our users with certain third parties. This information shows user activity as a whole rather than on an individual basis; such aggregate information cannot be used to individually identify you. We use aggregated information we collect about users to continue to improve our service for you. 

In the unlikely event that VolunteerMatch undergoes a sale or transfer of all or substantially all of its assets, the acquiring entity will be subject to this Privacy Policy in its use of your personally identifiable Information. In addition, in the further unlikely event that VolunteerMatch is adjudicated bankrupt or insolvent (a) there will be no further use or disclosure of your personally identifiable Information by VolunteerMatch and (b) your personally identifiable Information will be destroyed. In addition, there will be no use or disclosure of your personally identifiable Information by any entity that acquires assets of VolunteerMatch pursuant to such bankruptcy or insolvency proceedings. 

Due to factors beyond our control, however, we cannot fully ensure that your Information will not be disclosed to third parties. For example, we may be legally obligated to disclose Information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, or third parties may circumvent our security measures to unlawfully intercept or access your Personal Information. 

**Web Beacons**  
Our pages on www.volunteermatch.org may contain files called web beacons that we use for research and evaluation purposes. Information recorded through these beacons is used to report anonymous information about the results of pro-bono media campaigns donated by Yahoo!. Aggregate information may include demographic and usage information. You may choose to opt-out of this research by visiting: <http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/us/yahoo/opt_out/targeting/details.html>. 

**Links**  
This site contains links to other sites. VolunteerMatch is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

**How You Can Review Or Correct Your Information**  
If you are a nonprofit member or volunteer with a personal VolunteerMatch account (either through www.volunteermatch.org or a Partner's Web site) you may review and make changes to all of your Information that we collect and maintain online by simply inputting your username and password where indicated on the Web site. 

If you are a volunteer with a personal VolunteerMatch account, once you login in, you may make any changes or correct factual errors in your account by changing the information on your login page. This option is available 24 hours a day to better safeguard your Information, subject to downtime for standard maintenance and support. You do not need to contact us to access your record or to make any changes. If you have problems changing your Information, please contact Community Services at [support@volunteermatch.org](mailto:support@volunteermatch.org). 

**For Nonprofit or Other Volunteer Agencies**  
If you are an Agency administrator, you may make any changes or correct factual errors in your administrator, organization and opportunity information 24 hours a day. We use this procedure to better safeguard your Information. You do not need to contact us to access your record or to make any changes. If you have problems changing your Agency's Information, please contact Community Services at [support@volunteermatch.org](mailto:support@volunteermatch.org). 

If you are a nonprofit member or volunteer with an account and would like to have your Information deleted from the site, you may do so by contacting Community Services at [support@volunteermatch.org](mailto:support@volunteermatch.org). 

**Opting-out of Newsletters & Communications**  
Subscriptions to VolunteerMatch newsletters are optional and VolunteerMatch allows Agencies, volunteers, subscribers or other users to unsubscribe from newsletters at any time. In each newsletter we provide instructions regarding how to opt-out from receiving future newsletter mailings. You can also email us at [support@volunteermatch.org](mailto:support@volunteermatch.org) to remove your name from our newsletter subscription data base and ensure that you will cease receiving future newsletters from us. 

We may also use our email lists for sending out other VolunteerMatch outbound communications such as product enhancements, tool upgrades, or membership news. Registered members are required to receive these communications. 

**Our Commitment To Data Security**  
To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of Information, we have put in place reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the Information we collect online. 

**Changes to Policy**  
As part of the Terms of Service, this Privacy Policy is subject to occasional amendment, in accordance with the terms of the Terms of Service. 

**How To Contact Us**  
We appreciate your questions or comments about this privacy statement, the practices of this Web site, or your dealings with VolunteerMatch. Please send email to [support@volunteermatch.org](mailto:support@volunteermatch.org) or you can send snail mail to VolunteerMatch, 550 Montgomery Street, 8th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94111. 

Effective Date: May 31, 2008
